<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyber Security on live life to the fullest.</title>
    <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cyber Security on live life to the fullest.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja-jp</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://xingelf.github.io/sec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Request Smuggling (HRS)</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/http_request_smuggling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/http_request_smuggling/</guid>
      <description>Understanding HTTP Request Smuggling: A Deep Dive into Web Security In the dynamic world of web security, new threats and vulnerabilities continuously emerge, challenging the robustness of our digital infrastructures. Among these, HTTP request smuggling stands out as a complex yet intriguing exploit that targets the very foundations of how the web operates. This blog post aims to unravel the complexities of HTTP request smuggling, exploring its mechanisms, potential impacts, and effective countermeasures to safeguard against this sophisticated cyber threat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS)</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/cors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/cors/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS): A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide In the world of web development, security is paramount. One crucial aspect of securing web applications is understanding how to manage Cross-Origin Resource Sharing, commonly known as CORS. This concept can be a bit daunting for beginners, so in this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll break down CORS in a way that&amp;rsquo;s easy to understand and implement.&#xA;What is CORS? CORS is a security feature implemented by web browsers to prevent malicious websites from accessing resources from another domain without permission.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DIRB</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/dirb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/dirb/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the DIRB Command on Kali Linux: A Comprehensive Guide for Web Penetration Testing In the realm of web penetration testing, the ability to discover hidden or obscure resources on a web server is a critical skill. This is where the DIRB command comes into play, especially within the environment of Kali Linux, a preferred operating system among security professionals and ethical hackers. This blog post delves into the functionality of the DIRB command, illustrating its importance and providing practical guidance on how to effectively utilize this powerful tool.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSRF Cross Site Request Forgery</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/csrf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/csrf/</guid>
      <description>Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF) What is CSRF?&#xA;Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF) is a type of attack that forces a logged-in user to perform unwanted actions on a web application. The attacker tricks the user into submitting a malicious request to the web application, which the application then executes as if it were coming from the legitimate user.&#xA;How does CSRF work?&#xA;There are two main ways that CSRF attacks can be carried out:&#xA;Image tag attack: The attacker embeds an image tag on a malicious website that points to a URL on the victim&amp;rsquo;s web application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSRF Tokens</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/csrf_token/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/csrf_token/</guid>
      <description>CSRF Tokens: A Comprehensive Guide for Security Professionals Introduction&#xA;Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF) is a malicious attack that tricks a user&amp;rsquo;s browser into performing unintended actions on a trusted website where the user is logged in. This can lead to unauthorized data access, financial losses, and other serious consequences.&#xA;How CSRF Attacks Work:&#xA;Victim logs in: The victim logs into a trusted website (e.g., a bank) and their browser stores a session cookie. Attacker creates a malicious link or form: The attacker creates a link or form on a different website (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threat Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/threat_intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/threat_intelligence/</guid>
      <description>There are several categories of threat intelligence.&#xA;https://info-savvy.com/types-of-threat-intelligence/&#xA;Technical Threat Intelligence Technical cyber intelligence involves collecting information about the attacker&amp;rsquo;s resources, such as command &amp;amp; control channels and tools. For example, it focuses on technical clues that indicate cybersecurity threats to phishing emails and malicious URLs. The goal is to collect information on specific IOCs (IP addresses, phishing email headers, hash checksums). This type of threat intelligence is important because it allows for the analysis of attacks. However, the value of technical threat intelligence is short-lived because hackers often change tactics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DoS/DDoS Attack</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/dos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/dos/</guid>
      <description>Certainly! Below is the enhanced version of the article with additional details on each type of DDoS attack:&#xA;Understanding DDoS Attacks A Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attack is a malicious attempt to disrupt the normal operation of a targeted server, service, or network by overwhelming it with a flood of internet traffic. These attacks are executed by leveraging a multitude of compromised computer systems, often referred to as &amp;ldquo;bots&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;zombies,&amp;rdquo; which are under the control of the attacker. DDoS attacks can cause significant downtime, financial loss, and reputational damage to the targeted entity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hping/hping3使い方</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/hping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/hping/</guid>
      <description>hping/hping3は、ネットワークホストに様々な種類のパケットを送信し、その応答を分析することができるコマンドラインユーティリティです。 ネットワークスキャ</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rootkit ルートキット</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/rootkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/rootkit/</guid>
      <description>Rootkitにはいくつか種類があります。 https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rootkit カーネルレベル・ルートキット カーネルはオペレーティングシステムの中核であり、カーネルレベルルートキットは、デバイスド</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Engineering ソーシャルエンジニアリング</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/social_engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/social_engineering/</guid>
      <description>Social Engineeringとは ソーシャルエンジニアリングとは、不正な理由でターゲットに特定の情報を開示させたり、 特定の行動を取らせたりすることを目的としたすべての</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rootkit　ルートキット</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/rootkits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/rootkits/</guid>
      <description>Rootkitとは 侵入後のバックドアとして利用するツール・ソフトウェア群。ステルス化されており検出は困難。 Hypervisor Level Rootkit ハイパーバイザーレベルルートキット ハードウェアの</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNS Domain Name System</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/dns/</guid>
      <description>DNS DNS is essential in terms of the foot printing of the target. DNS gives us a lot of information. DNS探索は初期調査(footprinting)の基本動作です。 whois DNS管理組織は下表の通り。RIPEが欧州＋中東・中央</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer Virus/ウイルス 分類</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/computer_virus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/computer_virus/</guid>
      <description>ウイルス種類 ポリモーフィック型ウイルス いわゆる変異型。感染ごとに異なる鍵で暗号化し、パターンマッチによる検知を回避。 スペースフィラー型・キャヴィティ型ウイルス さ</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHNTPW　Windowsパスワード初期化・リセット</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/chntpw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/chntpw/</guid>
      <description>Kail LinuxをUSBブートしCHNTPWツールにてwindowsのパスワードをリセットできます。 administratorパスワードをロストした場合の復旧手段の</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TailgatingとPiggybackingの違い</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/tailgate_piggybacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/tailgate_piggybacking/</guid>
      <description>Tailgating 隠れて後ろからゲート通過 車で後ろから追走したり、後ろに付いてETCゲートなどを通過することから、 従業員がゲートを通過する際に後ろからひっそりと一緒に通過するこ</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Kill Chain サイバーキルチェーン</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/cyberkillchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/cyberkillchain/</guid>
      <description>サイバーキルチェーンとは https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kill_chain#Cyber ロッキードマーティン社のキルチェーンのプロセスをサイバー攻撃に適用したもの。 サイバー・キルチェーンは7つのステップで構成される。 1.偵</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pharming and Phising</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/phaming-phising/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/phaming-phising/</guid>
      <description>Pharming ファーミング https://csrc.nist.gov/glossary/term/pharming DNS（Domain Name System）などのインフラサービスを攻撃者が改ざんし、契約者を偽造した検証機/RPに誤誘導し、契約者に機密情報の漏洩や有</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nmap cheat nmapチート</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/nmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/nmap/</guid>
      <description>nmapとは ポートスキャンツールです。ペネトレーション作業の基本ツールです。 -T5 insane 最速でスキャンを実行 https://nmap.org/man/ja/man-performance.html -T4 Aggresive スキャン処理の遅延は10msec以内 -F 簡易スキャン nm</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rubber Hose Attack ゴムホース攻撃</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/rubber_hose_attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/rubber_hose_attack/</guid>
      <description>Rubber Hose Attack ゴムホース攻撃とは テクニカルな手法ではなく、物理的な手段などで人を脅迫してパスワードなどを入手する方法。 物理的な脅迫手段の１つとして、ゴムホースということ</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bluethoothを利用した攻撃</title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/buluetooth-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/buluetooth-attack/</guid>
      <description>Bluejacking ブルージャッキング 周囲にあるスマホなどのBluetoothデバイスへメッセージを送信する。 Bluesnarfing ブルースナーフィイング https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bluesnarfing ブルースナーフィングとは、Bluetoot</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/_idle_scan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xingelf.github.io/sec/_idle_scan/</guid>
      <description>アイドルスキャンは、TCPポートスキャンの手法の一つで、コンピュータになりすましたパケットを送信し、利用可能なサービスを調べるものである。これは、ネットワークト</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
